foreign
very good afternoon to all the viewers
one sector that is in focus is the
cement space in fact a lot of upgrades
downgrades a multiple you know it's a
pretty mixed Trend that we've been
witnessing but to discuss further as to
what's in store uh we have Navid Sade
from I says Securities joining in Naveen
uh good afternoon and welcome to the
show
Naveen my first question coming to you
is uh you know are the winds blowing in
favor of the cement sector right now
taking the way the demand is panning out
and from a volume growth perspective
definitely I think volumes are positive
that's the feedback I think March
quarter as such we saw record volumes
even the largest place like ultratech
said they run they ran like at near full
capacity especially in the month of
March as such and by and large I think
the feedback that we are getting is of
that demand momentum broadly sustaining
even in April and May so as far as
demand is concerned I think there is
definitely a positive trend or an
indication that is continuing I and I
think let me quickly add that it
shouldn't be that much of a surprise all
as well given it's a pre-election year
so we've sown what has happened in the
last three election which is FY 19 all
India demand through almost uh 13 this
year too I'm pretty hopeful it should it
should definitely be growing at the
bridge of Denver
right
regards to where the volume growth goes
now the second important aspect that
everyone wants to look at is as to how
the price trend is panning out right now
clearly uh if you see in terms of the
price trend there are Channel checks
suggesting anything in that range of
five rupees are back to 50 rupees a bag
is what they are going to push for but
how are the absorption levels in the
market currently
uh let me simplify it for you it's a
repeat of FY 19 for sure you will get
good volumes but no prices so whatever
feedback you said of companies trying
they have been trying six months now and
for the March quarter also the prices as
in companies reported realizations were
flat to Marginal negative and in most of
the earnings calls uh companies have
guided for again not to Marginal decline
even for the June quarter or so far into
the June quarter so prices is something
that we should not expect in FY 24 for
sure
okay and what according to you is the
key reason for that
it's the high competitive intensity
which we have been seeing for quite some
time now so let me put it this way that
even last year when the entire fuel cost
was facing these unprecedented surge as
a Fallout of the Russia Ukraine war even
in those adverse situation uh there
wasn't any pricing action which the
industry could demonstrate in fact in Q2
several companies reported uh very thin
ebitda margins
in some even reported losses what I'm
trying to highlight is that even in that
adverse scenario of a huge cost
escalation the industry could or
couldn't show any pricing power and
thereafter it has only weakened further
uh more so in busy Seasons uh like
December or even till May that we have
seen that the demand support is good but
High competitive intensity is keeping
cement prices weak or definitely not in
the rising Trend right now in another
aspect is in terms of earnings now
clearly if you look at fy22 and f523 the
earnings were under pressure but this
was mainly on the back of high raw
material prices the fuel cost was higher
uh even the demand that was slightly
muted in the previous years actually
prevented the companies from passing on
the high costs as well now that you see
the fuel cost which has started to
moderate uh do you think it will start
reflecting in the earnings of the cement
companies once the high cost inventory
actually gets mopped up and that's
something that we you know we should be
watching out for
uh sure so let me first of all clarify
that fy23 was again a very good year of
demand so we saw almost uh 11 12 kind of
a growth so that was by no means I'm
saying it was a moderate demand scenario
it was a healthy demand growth scenario
laid largely by South India as such but
we didn't see any pricing action and as
you rightly put it uh cost was high
which dented margins uh fy24 again I'm
like I said it will be a repeat of uh
very good demand
but I would like to believe that prices
will continue to be weak so even if your
cost is definitely coming down and it's
coming off pretty sharply much ahead of
I think streets expectations but the
underlying competitive intensity I think
will not let the entire uh cost benefits
accrue at the beta level most of it I
think will get passed on so I am
personally expecting on an annualized
basis only a marginal sort of a
Improvement in ebitda and definitely not
going back to those high levels that we
see in FY 20 or 21 right so Naveen
what's the kind of Blended epitaphatan
are you looking at in terms of an
increase because the street is looking
at at least 150 to 200 rupees per ton
increase do you think that is a
possibility is that you're baking in and
what are you baking in your estimates
so I'll have to be a little specific
here so Ultra tech for that matter uh
they closed the year FY 23 with about
approximately 1000 rupee of ebitda per
ton uh mind you march quarter was at
1050. so in my view uh this company
could do anywhere between 1050 to 1100
rupees and as you rightly put uh the
street estimate is more like 1200 or
1250 rupees I think that should be at a
risk given
pricing power is not there so we are
entering now into a seasonally week
period where historically prices have
tend to be tended to be weak and this
time more so uh there is reason for the
companies to be competitive because cost
is also coming down that much so I
largely view this as a as a spread
business where Nifty cost is falling uh
companies will give that much more like
you know benefit or pass it on that much
more to Consumers for the sake of market
share or to Garner more money
right now with an interesting aspect
that you pointed out was in terms of the
competitive intensity does this mean
that the sector will actually undergo a
healthy consolidation over the coming
years like we've we've seen a lot of
mergers Acquisitions that continue to
happen the latest is where you have JK
cement which has gone ahead acquired a
small one but in the Eastern region so
is it that you know companies with
higher net cash balance sheet are going
to follow the inorganic route to Ghana
market share then
I think I think mnd has been happening
in the sector and it has been happening
for a while now so MN days per se I'm
saying uh let's look at it this way that
despite all the elements that has
happened the top four or five players
continue to like you know hold about
four to five to fifty percent of the uh
industry while the balance uh 50 is with
over 30 40 players so these MN days or
talks of consolidation don't really help
much from a pricing perspective in fact
I look at it in a slightly different way
that while companies are trying to like
you know explore this route of expansion
be it uh be it any company for that
matter so whenever you acquire an asset
you have to introduce yourself you have
to relaunch yourself operate the set at
an optimal utilization that will in fact
lead to further pricing uh aggression or
competitive intensity for at least a
couple of quarters before settling down
right so if you have to look at the if
you know let's divide this between the
mid cap and the small cap cement players
as well as the large cap cement players
now if you have to look at the valuation
right from an EV uh by 10 ev2 turn uh
perspective the mid caps are usually at
the 35 to 40 discount to the large caps
right now if you take that Matrix into
consideration
and the way the market and the demand is
panning out now where are you seeing
value from an investment perspective
so we should look at uh consistency
rather than like you know there is a
reason why like you know the mid cap
straight at a discount the reasons could
be uh because of low margins that they
make and in turn that is a low Roe that
they generate uh at the same time at the
same time uh there is also what you say
uh
they have to in general High leverage on
the on the books as well so all these
put together leads to a low uh valuation
for these companies so you should look
at stocks where these issues are largely
addressed so one such mid cap stock we
have been pushing is JK cement uh
beautiful growth story consistent volume
visibility Best in Class Roes and uh
balance sheet is also fairly comfortable
or at least have peaked out so that is
those kind of names I'm saying
right and from a capacity Edition
perspective the kind of pipeline that we
are staring at how do you see it
impacting the utilization levels because
that seems to come across as a barrier
as well
so from a utilization perspective I
don't think uh it's really changing or
going drastically because
even for the next two to three years I'm
saying the capacity addition is going to
be fairly fairly high that 25 to 30
million tons uh kind of a range each
year and mind you Abuja is just started
they are they have a plan of uh doubling
in in five years so without that also
I'm saying there is enough and more
capacity addition that is happening in
Fr 24 25 and uh could add more to it
later on so from a utilization
perspective broadly don't see much
change to what were what they were in
fy23
right so overall you know Naveen my last
question coming to you is taking all the
aspects into consideration now let's
consider mid caps large caps all of them
where do you see value buying at current
levels with the valuations being
absolutely intact or favorable if you
have to pick up top stocks and what
would your view be
so frankly I have I don't have a
positive view on
the reason is like you said the
valuations are high while volumes are
supportive but in a commodity business
you need Rising power and that is
clearly at a mess
and this is like the running commentary
uh which I just shared but even from a
medium-term perspective I believe the
entry of ambuja and the aggression that
they are repeatedly like you know
conveying that they want to double
capacity that should keep in general the
addition and so the capacity Edition and
the pricing intensity high so I don't
find much Value Place uh currently uh it
in fact Ultra Tech and these names are
are trading definitely High we have a
reduced recommendation on three though
it is one of the best managed companies
but extremely high valuation so
we have a buy only on JK cement at this
point in time and if at all one has to
look for Value play then we are
recommending to play it through grassing
because that is where we see some value
coming up
right so grassum does come in as a topic
on that front and clearly if you see in
terms of today's session of trade as
well it's clearly Auto Tech which is the
top Gainer today grassum also comes up
in the top five gainers in terms of
nifty 50. thank you Naveen so much for
joining us on the show a pleasure to
speak to you as well and get insights in
terms of what could be in store for the
cement bag though all the levers seem to
be intact with the kind of announcements
that have been made by the government as
well in the budget there is good amount
of spending and expenditure from that
end and as Naveen was mentioning this
could be a repeat of what we saw in FY
19 where we could see good volume growth
but the concern is going to be in terms
of the pricing and that's something
which will not give them the Edge from a
margin perspective and the kind of
capacities that are coming on stream as
well that could have some bit of an
impact as well from a utilization
perspective so that's the overall view
that we have for all of you in terms of
the cement sector as a whole with grass
coming out to be naveen's top pick as
well so far that's all that we have on
this session thanks for watching and
lots more lined up on the other side
priesthood
[Music]
thank you